Guide to the John R. Bittner Papers, 1918-1994 and undated RL.10987
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John R. Bittner papers
1918-1994 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Bittner, John R., 1943-
RL.10987
3 Linear Feet 500 items
Professor of mass communications and administrator at University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John R. Bittner Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Collection Overview
Collection consists mainly of advertisements and some marketing and sales items collected by Bittner and used largely as source material for illustrating his publications. Formats comprising clipped advertisements (dating from 1919), tear sheets, storyboards, photographs, annual reports, news releases, and catalogs focus on products (including Coca-Cola), clothing, media (television and radio), and electronics. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Historical note
Biographical timeline
1943 May 4 Born, Greensburg, Pa.
1965-1967 Reporter, KXON AM-TV, MItchell, S.Dak.
1967 B.A., Curriculum in Educational Research, Dakota Wesleyan University
1968-1971 News Director, WAZY AM/FM, Lafayette, La.
1970 M.A., Communications, Purdue University
1972 PhD., Communications, Purdue Communications
1972-1973 Assistant Professor of Telecommunications, Director of Center for Media Research, University of Oregon
1977 Mass Communication: An Introduction (textbook); 2nd edition 1980; 3rd edition 1983; 4th edition 1986; 5th edition 1989; 6th edition 1996
1980 Broadcasting: An Introduction (textbook); 2nd edition (as Broadcasting and Telecommunication) 1985; 3rd edition 1991
1980-2002 University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill: positions with the Department of Communication Studies (1980-1983); Department of Radio, Television and Motion Pictures (1980-1990); Graduate School (1984-1990); School of Journalism and Mass Communication (1991-2002)
1985 Fundamentals of Communication (textbook); 2nd edition 1988
1973-1980 Associate Professor of Communications Arts and Sciences, Director of Broadcast Communications, Depauw University General Manager, WGRE-FM, Greencastle, Ind. (PBS affiliate at Depauw University)
2002 Apr. 9 Died, Chapel Hill, N.C.
Photographs; Press releases; Marketing; Mass media -- United States; Advertising -- Brand name products.; Brand name products -- United States; Brand name products -- Marketing; Radio advertising; Television advertising; Advertising -- Clothing and dress; Advertising -- Data processing.; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Coca-Cola Company; Bittner, John R., 1943-
- John R. Bittner papers, 1918-1994 and undated
  - Bittner resume, 1943-2002 (Box 1)
  - 1-800 Collect, undated (Box 1)
  - America Online, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Apple Computer, undated (Box 1)
  - Arbitron, 1977-1993 (Box 1)
  - Arbitron, 1977-1993 (Box 1)
  - Arbitron, 1977-1993 (Box 1)
  - CBS News, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Charles Michelson Inc., undated (Box 1)
  - Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Coca-Cola, 1988 and undated (Box 1)
  - Columbia Phonograph, circa 1905 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Public Information (WWI), undated (Box 1)
  - CompuServe, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Direct Marketing Association, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Harry & Dave (Bear Creek Orchard), 1936 and undated (Box 1)
  - Hearst Magazines, undated (Box 1)
  - Hitchcock Marketing Services, 1978 (Box 1)
  - King World Productions, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Kodak, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Land's End, 1990 (Box 1)
  - L.L. Bean, undated (Box 1)
  - Hewlett-Packard, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, undated (Box 2)
  - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, undated (Box 2)
  - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, undated (Box 2)
  - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, undated (Box 2)
  - National Archives WWII 50th Anniversary Commemoration, 1991-1995 (Box 2)
  - National Association of Broadcasters, 1980 (Box 2)
  - National Black Network, 1981-1988 (Box 2)
  - NBC-TV Network, undated (Box 2)
  - NCNB (North Carolina National Bank; McKinney & Silver storyboards), 1983 (Box 2)
  - NEC, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Office of War Information (WWII), undated (Box 2)
  - Panasonic, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  - Radio Havana Cuba, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Roadside Americana (Mail Pouch sign), undated (Box 2)
  - Sesame Street, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Sheet music, When Lindy Comes Home (George M. Cohan), 1927 (Box 2)
  - Spiegel history, 1964-1989 (Box 2)
  - Talbot's, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Texas Instruments, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Time Magazine, March of Time, 1934 (Box 2)
  - United Airlines Japanese inflight magazine, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Universal Data/Motorola, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Westinghouse, undated (Box 2)
  - Windjammer Cruises, undated (Box 2)
  - WWII Liberty Loan posters, undated (Box 2)
  - Xerox, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Yankee Publishing, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Bell Telephone/AT&T, undated (Box 3)
  - Columbia Phonograph, 1918-1920 and undated (Box 3)
  - Coca-Cola, 1974 and undated (Box 3)
  - Dispatch News Service, 1927-1928 (Box 3)
  - Electric appliances--Burroughs, General Electric, Radiola, Sparton Radio, 1923-1969 (Box 3)
  - International--Jewelite food stores (Spanish), Mitsubishi/Tobishi/Honda (Japanese), 1988 and undated (Box 3)
  - Media--Casey Kasem, CBS News, Coventry Romances, Licensing Corporation, MTV News, Nelson Doubleday, Pictorial Review, Washington Post, WWBT, 1931-1989 and undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous--Black Velvet (Larry Hagman), Blue Cross Blue Shield, Christian Dior, GE lamps, Hermosillo/Lassen County, Karo, Kemper-Thomas, LL Bean, Lux/Spencer Corsets, Muriel Cigars (Susan Anton), Old Grand Dad, Pabst/White Trucks, Revlon Scoundrel, Snider's Catsup, US Tape and Label, 1919-1982 and undated (Box 3)
  - Photography--Kinetoscope, Kodak, Minox, Sony, undated (Box 3)
  - Public Service--Distilled Spirits Council, Have a Nice Day, Minnesota Department of Public Safety, Tri-a-Ride, US Department of Transportation (Lorne Green), 1993 and undated (Box 3)
  - Telephone/Telegraph--British Telecom, Wireless Telegraph Signal, undated (Box 3)
  - Travel/Transportation--Dollar Rent-a-Car, Hertz (OJ Simpson), Hotel del Monte/Palace Hotel, Rock Island, Stevens-Duryea, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous--Carolina Power & Light, Philips, Royal Caribbean, 1994 (Box 4)
  - WWII Liberty Loan poster, undated (Box 4)